## **TONI ANEV**

Results driven data analyst with a passion for analytics and process automation. A self-starter who enjoys the challenge of complex technical problems and is able to aggregate, condense and communicate complex insights in clear and accessible ways.

Extensive experience working with large-scale data sets, programming languages and visualization tools in both research and business environments. Relentlessly curious and driven to learn about emerging technologies and dive deep into the intricacies of how things work behind the scenes.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### DATA SCIENTIST, LOBLAW COMPANIES LTD

Toronto, Canada | January 2019 - Present

- Designed and productionized an automated software tool aimed at maximizing department revenue by forecasting optimal product pricing and markdown timing using Python, SQL, HTML/CSS/JavaScript and Spark in Azure HDInsight.
- Worked closely with various cross-functional teams and senior leaders to conduct A/B tests, impact analyses, data validation and decisioning automation resulting in division profit increase of \$15-20M (~25% improvement) annually.
- Developed data pipelines (Python, SQL, GCP, Teradata) related to media campaign delivery and insight gathering from Facebook Business Manager and Google DV360 aimed at increasing department revenue by 42M annually.
- Design customer attribution and segmentation models aimed at leveraging transactional and web behaviour data to identify active users, increase retention, predict churn rates and deliver highly personalized advertising to customers.
- Implement methodologies that empower C-suite executives and key decision makers with reliable performance metrics relating to product performance, revenue projections, customer segmentation and retention.
- Communicate findings and solutions to a broad range of technical and nontechnical audiences in addition to authoring and maintaining detailed code documentation and version control.

#### **DATA ANALYST, NUMERIS**

Toronto, Canada | September 2016 – January 2019

- Designed Python and PL/SQL scripts to automate data extraction, wrangling and error checking processes resulting in +90% processing efficiency.
- Designed PL/SQL scripts to manage system generated work orders by inserting and updating action/state codes into normalized production database, automating 10 days of work effort across 2 departments.
- Automated report generation of employee performance metrics and panelist behavior insights using Python and PL/SQL resulting in +95% process efficiency.
- Performed in depth analysis of national research sample data to optimize universe rim weighting changes, population demographic updates, reception type updates and geographic cell changes.
- Worked cross-functionally with teams to identify business and research requirements leading to the development of KPIs, insight reports and database security updates.

**RESEARCH ANALYST,** UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO, FACULTY OF MEDICINE Toronto, Canada | 2014 – 2015

- Cleansed, organized and analyzed faculty research data to help leaders make informed funding decisions.
- Prepared reports and communication for senior management to ensure relevant and consistent internal communications.
- Created and presented visualizations to senior leadership relating to researcher collaboration metrics and overall department research focus areas.

647-282-6935 tonianev@gmail.com www.tonianev.com

github:

www.github.com/tonianev

linkedin:

www.linkedin.com/in/tonianev

#### **EDUCATION**

**Data Scientist Nanodegree** 

Udacity Inc. | 2020

**Data Analyst Nanodegree** 

Udacity Inc. | 2018

**Bachelor of Science** 

McMaster University | 2012 – 16

#### **EXPERTISE**

Python (pandas, numpy, django etc.)
SQL (Oracle, Teradata, BigQuery etc.)
Tableau / Cytoscape / Matplotlib
Node.js / Express.js / Mongo DB
Databricks / Jupyter / Spyder
Hadoop / Spark / Eagle Eye
R (knitr, ggplot2, dplyr etc.)
HTML5 / CSS / JavaScript
Azure / GCP / AWS
Git / Bitbucket

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

# Machine Learning in Image Processing

Google Developer Group | 2020 <u>Course Certificate</u>

Machine Learning, Data Science and Deep Learning with Python

Udemy | 2019

Course Certificate

Machine Learning A-Z: Python & R in Data Science

Udemy | 2018 Course Certificate

#### **AWARDS**

**Entrance Scholarship Recipient** 

McMaster University, 2012

**Honors for Academic Excellence** 

Burnhamthorpe Collegiate Institute, 2012

Honors for Academic Excellence

Martingrove Collegiate Institute, 2010